urlscan.io - Privacy Policy
===========================

Last updated: July 22, 2020

Thank you for using our service at urlscan.io. This privacy policy will explain how our company uses the personal data we collect from you when you use our service. Please read this privacy policy carefully as it will help you make informed decisions about sharing your personal data with us. **If you do not agree with our policy, do not use our service or provide urlscan.io with your personal data.** If you have any questions about our policy, or our practices with regards to your personal information, please contact us at privacy@urlscan.io.

Definitions
-----------

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy:

* **You** means the individual accessing or using the Service, or the company, or other legal entity on behalf of which such individual is accessing or using the Service, as applicable.
* **Company** (referred to as either "the Company", "We", "Us" or "Our" in this Agreement) refers to urlscan GmbH, Kuhlweg 6b, 52074 Aachen, Germany
* **Account** means a unique account created for you to access our Service or parts of our Service.
* **Website** refers to urlscan, accessible from urlscan.io
* **Service** refers to the Website.
* **Personal Data** is any information that relates to an identified or identifiable individual.
* **Cookies** are small files that are placed on your computer, mobile device or any other device by a website, for the purpose of establishing a unique user identification token for the duration of the service being used.
* **Usage Data** refers to data collected automatically, either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).

What data do We collect?
------------------------

### Personal Data

We collect personal information that You voluntarily/directly provide to Us when registering at the Service, when using Our Service or otherwise contacting Us.

Personal Data may include, but is not limited to:

* Email address
* First and last name
* Company name and job title
* Usage Data

### Usage Data

Usage Data is collected automatically when using the Service. This information does not reveal Your specific identity (like Your name or contact information) but may include device and usage information, such as Your IP address, browser and device characteristics, operating system, language preferences, referring URLs, device name, country, location, information about how and when You use Our Service and other technical information. This information is primarily needed to maintain the security and operation of Our Service, and for Our internal analytics and reporting purposes.

### Cookies

When You visit Our Website, We may collect information from You automatically through Cookies or similar technology. Our Company uses Cookies in a range of ways to improve Your experience on Our Website, including, (but not limited to): Keeping You signed in to the service and re-establishing your user identity.

Our Website only uses essential session Cookies, that are strictly necessary to provide You with services available through the Website and to enable You to use some of its features. They help to authenticate users and prevent fraudulent use of user accounts. Without these Cookies, the services that You have asked for cannot be provided, and We only use these Cookies to provide You with those services.

You can set Your browser not to accept Cookies, and the above website tells You how to remove Cookies from Your browser. However, (in a few cases), some of Our Website’s features may not function as a result.

How will We use Your data?
--------------------------

We may use Personal Data for the following purposes:

* To create and manage user accounts. We may use Your information for the purposes of managing Your account and keeping it in working order.
* To send administrative information to You. We may use Your personal information to send You product, service and new feature information and/or information about changes to Our terms, conditions, and policies.
* To protect Our Service. We may use Your information as part of Our efforts to keep Our Service safe and secure (for example, for fraud monitoring and prevention).
* To manage Your requests. We may use Your information to attend and manage Your requests to Us.

Will Your Information be shared with anyone?
--------------------------------------------

We may process or share data based on the following legal basis:

* **Consent**: We may process Your data if You have given Us specific consent to use Your data for a specific purpose.
* **Contractual Obligations**: Where We have entered into a contract with You, We may process Your personal information to fulfill the terms of Our contract.
* **Legitimate Interests**: We may process Your data when it is reasonably necessary to achieve Our legitimate business interests.
* **Legal Obligations**: We may disclose Your information where We are legally required to do so in order to comply with applicable law, governmental requests, a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena (including in response to public authorities to meet national security or law enforcement requirements).
* **Vital Interests**: We may disclose Your information where We believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding potential violations of Our policies, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person and illegal activities, or as evidence in litigation in which We are involved.

More specifically, We may need to process Your data or share Your personal information in the following situations:

* **Business Transfers**: We may share or transfer Your information if Our Company is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale. We will provide notice before Your Personal Data is transferred and becomes subject to a different Privacy Policy.

How do We store and process Your data?
--------------------------------------

Your data is processed at the Company's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by Your submission of such information represents Your agreement to that transfer.

The Company will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that Your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of Your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of Your data and other personal information.

The security of Your Personal Data is important to Us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While We strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect Your Personal Data, We cannot guarantee its absolute security.

How long do We keep Your data?
------------------------------

We will only keep Your personal information for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (such as tax, accounting or other legal requirements). No purpose in this policy will require Us keeping Your personal information for longer than the period of time in which users have an account with us.

When We have no ongoing legitimate business need to process Your personal information, We will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because Your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store Your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

What are Your data protection rights?
-------------------------------------

We would like to make sure You are fully aware of all of Your data protection rights. Every user is entitled to the following:

* **The right to access -** You have the right to request Our Company for copies of Your Personal Data. We may charge You a small fee for this service.
* **The right to rectification** - You have the right to request that Our Company correct any information You believe is inaccurate. You also have the right to request Our Company to complete information You believe is incomplete.
* **The right to erasure** \- You have the right to request that Our Company erase Your Personal Data, under certain conditions.
* **The right to restrict processing** \- You have the right to request that Our Company restrict the processing of Your Personal Data, under certain conditions.
* **The right to object to processing** - You have the right to object to Our Company's processing of Your Personal Data, under certain conditions.
* **The right to data portability** \- You have the right to request that Our Company transfer the data that We have collected to another organization, or directly to You, under certain conditions.

If You make a request, We have one month to respond to You. If You would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact Us at Our email: info@urlscan.io

Account Information
-------------------

If You would at any time like to review or change the information in Your account or terminate Your account, You can:

* Contact Us using the contact information provided.
* Log into Your account settings and update Your user account.

Upon Your request to terminate Your account, We will deactivate or delete Your account and information from Our active databases. However, some information may be retained in Our files to prevent fraud, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce Our Terms of Use and/or comply with legal requirements.

You can unsubscribe from Our email list at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the emails that We send or by contacting Us using the details provided below. You will then be removed from the email list – however, We will still need to send You service-related emails that are necessary for the administration and use of Your account. To otherwise opt-out, You may:

* Contact Us using the contact information provided.
* Access Your account settings and update preferences.
* Note Your preferences when You register an account with Our Service.

Do We collect Information from Minors
-------------------------------------

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 18 years of age. By using the Service, You represent that You are at least 18 or that You are the parent or guardian of such a minor and consent to such minor dependent’s use of the Service.

If We become aware that personal information from users less than 18 years of age has been collected, We will deactivate the account and take reasonable measures to promptly delete such data from Our records. If You become aware of any data We have collected from children under age 18, please contact Us at privacy@urlscan.io.

Privacy policies of other websites
----------------------------------

Our Service may contain links to other websites that are not operated by Us. If You click on a third party link, You will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise You to review the Privacy Policy of every site You visit. We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

Changes to Our privacy policy
-----------------------------

Urlscan reserves the right to update this privacy policy at any time. We will notify You either by prominently posting a notice of such changes and update the “latest update” date at the top of this page or by directly sending You a notification.

We strongly recommend reviewing this privacy policy frequently for any changes.

Copyright © 2023, urlscan GmbH  
Version:

#### 0 0

#### 0 0 0

Page generated on 2024-08-01 16:26:59
